<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CSC13009-Android-CKDP</string>

    //Firts Aid
    <string name="title_firstaid">First Aid</string>
    <string name="title_animalbite">Animal Bites</string>
    <string name="title_brokenbone">Broken Bone</string>
    <string name="title_burn">Burn</string>
    <string name="title_choking">Choking</string>
    <string name="title_cut">Cut</string>
    <string name="title_drowning">Drowning</string>
    <string name="title_electricshock">Electric Shock</string>
    <string name="title_emergency">Emergency</string>
    <string name="title_heartattack">Heart Attack</string>
    <string name="title_nosebleeding">Nose Bleed</string>
    <string name="title_poisonousplant">Poisonous Plant</string>
    <string name="title_sprain">Sprain</string>
    <string name="title_stroke">Stroke</string>
    <string name="title_thorns">Thorns</string>
    <string name="firstaid">
How do I make a first aid kit.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009A well-stocked first aid kit is a must-have for treating minor injuries at home and on the go. You can buy a first aid kit or put one together on your own. Keep your supplies in a sturdy, clear plastic box so you can see what’s inside.\n

What should be in my first aid kit?\n

\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Adhesive tape\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Alcohol wipes\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Allergy medicine\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Aloe vera gel\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Antibiotic ointment\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Bandages in different sizes\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Calamine lotion\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Cold packs\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Elastic bandages\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Gauze rolls and pads\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hand sanitizer (for your travel first aid kit)\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hydrocortisone cream\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Latex-free gloves\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Pain relievers like acetaminophen and ibuprofen\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Saline wound wash\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Scissors and tweezers
    </string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis">
Anaphylaxis (or anaphylactic shock) is a severe allergic reaction that can occur after an insect sting or after eating certain foods. The adverse reaction can be very fast, occurring within seconds or minutes of coming into contact with the substance the person is allergic to (allergen).\n\nDuring anaphylactic shock, it may be difficult for the person to breathe, as their tongue and throat may swell, obstructing their airway.\n\nPhone 999 or 112 immediately if you think someone is experiencing anaphylactic shock.\n\nCheck if the person is carrying any medication. Some people who know they have severe allergies may carry an adrenaline self-injector, which is a type of pre-loaded syringe. You can either help the person administer their medication or, if you are trained to do so, give it to them yourself.\n\nAfter the injection, continue to look after the person until medical help arrives. All casualties who have had an intramuscular or subcutaneous (under the skin) injection of adrenaline must be seen and medically checked by a healthcare professional as soon as possible after the injection has been given.\n\nMake sure they are comfortable and can breathe as best they can while waiting for medical help to arrive. If they are conscious, sitting upright is normally the best position for them.
    </string>
    <string name="animalbite">
How do I treat animal bites and scratches?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Sometimes a seemingly friendly dog or cat can bite or scratch. If you or your child gets a bite, follow these steps to treat the wound:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hold a towel or gauze to the area to stop the bleeding.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Clean the wound with soap and water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Cover it with a clean bandage or gauze pad.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009When should I see a doctor for an animal bite?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009For any animal bite, you may need an antibiotic to prevent infection. So it’s always a good idea to call your doctor, especially if you have medical conditions that weaken your immune system. Also, you should call your doctor or head to the emergency room if:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The bite was caused by an animal you don’t know, or by any wild animal like a raccoon, skunk, or bat. You may need a tetanus or rabies vaccine.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The bite is large, or it doesn’t stop bleeding after you’ve held pressure on it for 15 minutes. It may need to be closed with stitches.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You think the bite may have damaged a bone, tendons, or nerves, because you can’t bend or straighten the body part or you’ve lost feeling in it.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The wound is red, swollen, or oozing fluid.\nHow do I treat bee, wasp, and other insect stings?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Here’s what to do:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- If the insect has left behind a stinger, remove it from the skin so less of the venom gets into your body. You can scrape out the stinger with the edge of a credit card or the dull edge of a knife. Don’t squeeze the stinger. You might release more of the venom into your skin.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Once the stinger is out or if there is no stinger, wash the area around the sting with soap and water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hold an ice pack or cool washcloth to the sting to stop it from swelling.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Spread calamine lotion or baking soda mixed with water to relieve pain.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- To prevent itching, use a spray or cream containing hydrocortisone or antihistamine.\nRELATED\nHow do I treat a mosquito bite?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Here’s what to do:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Apply firm pressure to the bite for 10 seconds to help stop the itch.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Use a baking soda paste or hydrocortisone cream 4 times a day to relieve itching. Don’t have either on hand? Holding ice or a wet washcloth on the bite will also help.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Take an antihistamine if the bite is very itchy.\nWhat are the signs that my child is allergic to the insect?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009It’s normal for the skin around the insect sting to swell up and get red. But call 911 or go to the emergency room if you see any of these signs of an allergic reaction:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Dizziness\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hives — red, itchy bumps on the skin\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Stomach cramps, vomiting, or diarrhea\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Swelling of the tongue\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Trouble breathing, wheezing\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Anyone who has allergies to bees, wasps, or other stinging insects should keep an epinephrine auto-injector at home, work, and school in case of a sting.\nHow do I treat a spider bite?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009For most of the harmless types of spiders you’ll find at home, treatment is pretty simple:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wash the area with soap and water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hold an ice pack or cool washcloth to the bite to relieve pain and bring down swelling.\nHow do I know if a spider is poisonous?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Spiders might be creepy and crawly, but most of them aren’t poisonous. The poisonous spiders to watch out for are the brown recluse and black widow. Here’s how to spot them:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Brown recluse spiders are about 1/2-inch long. They’re brown and have a mark in the shape of a violin on their back.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Black widow spiders are black with a red hourglass-shaped mark on their stomach.\nWhat should I do for a poisonous spider bite?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If you think you were bitten by a poisonous spider like a brown recluse or black widow, call 911 or go to the emergency room right away. Look for these signs:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A red or purple color around the bite\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Pain in the bite area\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Swelling around the bite\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Muscle pain and cramps\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Fever\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Chills\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Rash\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Stomach pain\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Nausea and vomiting\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Trouble breathing
    </string>
    <string name="brokenbone">
It can be difficult to tell if a person has a broken bone or a joint, as opposed to a simple muscular injury. If you are in any doubt, treat the injury as a broken bone.\n\nIf the person is unconscious, has difficulty breathing or is bleeding severely, these must be dealt with first, by controlling the bleeding with direct pressure and performing CPR.\n\nIf the person is conscious, prevent any further pain or damage by keeping the fracture as still as possible until you get them safely to hospital.\n\nAssess the injury and decide whether the best way to get them to hospital is by ambulance or car. For example, if the pain isn’t too severe, you could transport them to hospital by car. It is always best to get someone else to drive, so that you can deal with the casualty if they deteriorate – for example, if they lose consciousness as a result of the pain or start to vomit.\n\nHowever, if:\n\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- They’re in a lot of pain and in need of strong painkilling medication, do not move them and phone an ambulance\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- It is obvious they have a broken leg, do not move them, but keep them in the position you found them in and phone an ambulance\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You suspect they have injured or broken their back, do not move them and phone an ambulance\n\nDo not give the casualty anything to eat or drink, because they may need an anaesthetic (numbing medication) when they reach hospital.
    </string>
    <string name="burn">
What are the different types of burns?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Grabbing a hot pot or splashing boiling water on your skin are just two common causes of burns around the house. When you get a burn, first check to see which type it is. Some are more serious than others.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- First-degree burns are painful but minor. They turn red and may swell.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Second-degree burns form blisters. The skin may be very red and painful.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Third-degree burns make the skin look white or charred. The burns may not hurt because nerves have been damaged.\nWhen should I see a doctor?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Serious burns need to be treated by a doctor or in a hospital. Call for medical help if:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You have a third-degree burn.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The burn is larger than 2 to 3 inches.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The burn is on your face, hands, feet, or over a joint like your shoulder or knee.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The burn goes all the way around a hand, arm, foot, or leg.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The pain gets worse instead of better.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The burn was caused by electricity or a chemical.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You see fluid or pus oozing from the burn.\nHow do I treat burns?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009You can treat minor first-degree burns and small second-degree burns at home. Here’s what to do:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Place the burned area under running cool water for at least 5 minutes to reduce swelling.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Apply an antiseptic spray, antibiotic ointment, or aloe vera cream to soothe the area.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Loosely wrap a gauze bandage around the burn.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- To relieve pain, take acetaminophen, ibuprofen, or naproxen.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Never put butter on a burn or pop any blisters that form. You could damage the skin and cause an infection.\nHow do I treat a sunburn?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Always wear sunscreen when you’re outdoors to protect your skin from the sun. If you stay outside for too long without protection, you can get a red, itchy burn that may blister. As soon as you spot a sunburn, head inside to treat it.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Soothe your burned skin with a cool, damp washcloth. Or take a cool shower or bath. Pat your skin dry afterward. Be gentle — your sunburn may be sore.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Apply an aloe vera lotion. Or use a hydrocortisone cream to relieve the itch. Do not use lotions that contain petroleum, benzocaine, or lidocaine. These ingredients can irritate the skin even more.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- If the sunburn is really sore, take acetaminophen, ibuprofen, or naproxen to relieve the pain.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A sunburn can dry out your body. Drink extra water so you won’t get dehydrated.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Give your sunburn time to heal. Cover your burned skin with clothing and a hat to protect it when you go outside.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- See a doctor if you have blisters on the sunburn, or you get a fever or chills. Don’t pop the blisters. They could get infected.
    </string>
    <string name="choking">
Mild choking\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If the airway is only partly blocked, the person will usually be able to speak, cry, cough or breathe. In situations like this, a person will usually be able to clear the blockage themselves.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If choking is mild:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Encourage the person to cough to try to clear the blockage\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Ask them to try to spit out the object if it’s in their mouth\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Do not put your fingers in their mouth to help them because they may accidentally bite you\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If coughing doesn’t work, start back blows (see below).\nSevere choking\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If choking is severe, the person won’t be able to speak, cry, cough or breathe, and without help they’ll eventually become unconscious.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009To help an adult or child over one year old:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Stand behind the person and slightly to one side. Support their chest with one hand. Lean the person forward so that the object blocking their airway will come out of their mouth, rather than moving further down.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Give up to five sharp blows between the person’s shoulder blades with the heel of your hand (the heel is between the palm of your hand and your wrist).\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Check if the blockage has cleared.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- If not, give up to five abdominal thrusts (see below).\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Abdominal thrusts should not be used on babies under one year old, pregnant women or obese people.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009To perform abdominal thrusts on a person who is severely choking and isn’t in one of the above groups:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Stand behind the person who is choking.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Place your arms around their waist and bend them well forward.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Clench one fist and place it just above the person is belly button.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Place your other hand on top of your fist and pull sharply inwards and upwards.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Repeat this up to five times.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009The aim is to get the obstruction out with each chest thrust, rather than necessarily doing all five.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If the obstruction does not clear after three cycles of back blows and chest thrusts, phone 999 or 112 to ask for an ambulance, and continue until help arrives.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009The person choking should always be seen by a healthcare professional afterwards to check for any injuries or small pieces of the obstruction that remain.
    </string>
    <string name="cut">
Follow these steps to keep cuts clean and prevent infections and scars.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Step 1: Wash your hands. First, wash up with soap and water so you don’t get bacteria into the cut and cause an infection. If you’re on the go, use hand sanitizer.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Step 2: Stop the bleeding. Put pressure on the cut with a gauze pad or clean cloth. Keep the pressure on for a few minutes.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Step 3: Clean the wound. Once you’ve stopped the bleeding, rinse the cut under cool running water or use a saline wound wash. Clean the area around the wound with soap and a wet washcloth. Don’t get soap in the cut, because it can irritate the skin. And don’t use hydrogen peroxide or iodine, which could irritate the cut.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Step 4: Remove any dirt or debris. Use a pair of tweezers cleaned with alcohol to gently pick out any dirt, gravel, glass, or other material in the cut.\nDo I need to bandage a cut or scrape?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009You don’t need to bandage every cut and scrape. Some heal more quickly when left uncovered to stay dry. But if the cut is on a part of the body that might get dirty or rub against clothes, put on a bandage to protect it. Change the bandage every day or whenever it gets wet or dirty.\nHow long should a cut or scrape be covered?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Once a solid scab has formed, you can take off the bandage.\nWhen do I need to call my doctor?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Check with your doctor or go to the emergency room if:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The cut is deep, long, or the edges are jagged. You may need stitches and a tetanus shot.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The cut or scrape is from a dirty or rusty object. You may need a tetanus shot.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The injury is from an animal or human bite.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You can’t stop the bleeding with direct pressure.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You can’t get dirt out of the wound.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The cut is on your face or near a joint, like on your fingers.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The skin around the cut gets red and swollen or develops red streaks.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Pus drains from the cut.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You have a fever of more than 100.4 F (in either an adult or child).\nHow do topical antibiotic ointments work?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Topical antibiotics are medicines you put on your skin to kill bacteria. Most cuts and scrapes will heal without ointment, but they can reduce scars and help the wound heal faster. If you do use an antibiotic ointment, apply it to your skin one to three times a day and then cover with a clean bandage.\nWhen should I use gauze and tape?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Gauze and tape work best for large cuts and scrapes that bandages won’t cover. Ask your pharmacist which type of gauze is best for you.\nHow should I apply gauze and tape?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wash your hands with soap and water. You can also wear gloves.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Gently wash the wound with a wet piece of gauze or washcloth.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Place a piece of clean gauze over the wound.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Apply tape around the edges of the gauze to hold it in place.\nHow do I prevent scars?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009When your body heals after a cut, scrape, or burn, sometimes a scar can be left behind. Depending on the injury, some scars are small, and others are bigger and more noticeable.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009To prevent scars, follow these tips:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wear helmets, kneepads, and other protective gear to avoid injury.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Treat any cuts or other wounds right away.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Keep the wound moist (try an antibiotic ointment or petroleum jelly) while it heals.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Don’t pick at the scab.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Consider covering your cut with silicone gel sheeting, a clear, sticky pad that can speed healing.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- If the scar isn’t fading, ask your doctor about creams or ointments to make it less obvious
    </string>
    <string name="drowning">
If someone is in difficulty in water, do not enter the water to help unless it is absolutely essential.\n\nOnce the person is on land, if they are not breathing, open the airway and give five initial rescue breaths before starting CPR. If you are alone, perform CPR for one minute before phoning for emergency help.\n\nFind out how to give CPR, including rescue breaths.\n\nIf the person is unconscious but still breathing, put them into the recovery position with their head lower than their body and phone an ambulance immediately.\n\nContinue to observe the casualty to ensure they do not stop breathing or that their airway becomes obstructed
    </string>
    <string name="electricshock">
If someone has had an electric shock, switch off the electrical current at the mains to break the contact between the person and the electrical supply.\nIf you can not reach the mains supply:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Do not go near or touch the person until you are sure the electrical supply has been switched off\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Once the power supply has been switched off, and if the person is not breathing, phone 999 or 112 for an ambulance\nAfterwards, seek medical help - unless the electric shock is very minor.
    </string>
    <string name="emergency">
Call 911 for any medical emergency, including when a person has:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Chest pain\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A serious allergic reaction\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009 -Bleeding that won’t stop\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Trouble breathing\nWhat should I do when I call 911?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Tell the operator:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The type of emergency\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The telephone number you’re calling from\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The address where the emergency is happening\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Details about the person’s condition — what happened to them, the type of injuries they have, and what has been done so far to treat them\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009The 911 operator might tell you step by step how to help the person who has been injured. DO NOT HANG UP until the operator hangs up.\nHow can I prepare for an emergency?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Keep a fully stocked first-aid kit in your home and car.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Have up-to-date copies of each person’s medical history in your home and car.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Post an emergency contact sheet next to each phone in the house. Show it to everyone who spends time in your home, including family members and babysitters.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Make sure your children know what number to dial — 911 — and what they should tell the operator.
    </string>
    <string name="heartattack">
A heart attack is one of the most common life-threatening heart conditions in the UK.\nIf you think a person is having, or has had, a heart attack, sit them down and make them as comfortable as possible, and phone 999 or 112 for an ambulance.\nSymptoms of a heart attack include:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Chest pain – the pain is usually located in the centre or left side of the chest and can feel like a sensation of pressure, tightness or squeezing\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Pain in other parts of the body – it can feel as if the pain is travelling from the chest down one or both arms, or into the jaw, neck, back or abdomen (tummy)\nSit the person down and make them comfortable.\nIf they are conscious, reassure them and ask them to take a 300mg aspirin tablet to chew slowly (unless you know they should not take aspirin – for example, if they are under 16 or allergic to it).\nIf the person has any medication for angina, such as a spray or tablets, help them to take it. Monitor their vital signs, such as breathing, until help arrives.\nIf the person deteriorates and becomes unconscious, open their airway, check their breathing and, if necessary, start CPR. Re-alert the emergency services that the casualty is now in cardiac arrest.
    </string>
    <string name="nosebleeding">
How do I treat a nosebleed?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Nosebleeds usually look a lot worse than they are. Most of the time you can stop the flow with a few simple steps:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Lean the head slightly forward, so blood doesn’t run down the throat.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- With a tissue or washcloth, gently press the nostrils together to stop the bleeding.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hold the nose for at least 5 minutes. Then check to see if the bleeding has stopped. If it hasn’t stopped, gently squeeze for another 10 minutes.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Call the doctor or go to an emergency room if:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The bleeding hasn’t stopped after 15 to 20 minutes or keeps starting again.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The bleeding is fast and there’s a lot of blood.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- The bleeding is from an injury to your nose or face.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- You feel faint or weak.
    </string>
    <string name="poisonousplant">
How do I treat a rash from poison ivy or other poisonous plants?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009When you touch poison ivy — or poison oak or sumac — the rash that appears on your skin is caused by an oil in the plant. The rash may itch and blister. But it should go away on its own within a few weeks.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Treat the rash and itch at home with these steps:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wash your skin. To get as much of the oil off as possible, clean your skin with soap and lukewarm water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wash everything. Clean anything the plant touched — your clothes, gardening tools, even your pet. The oil can stick to these objects and cause a rash if you touch them again.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Bathe in oatmeal. Run a warm bath and add some colloidal oatmeal or baking soda to ease the itch. You can also apply a cool, wet washcloth to your skin.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Apply calamine or hydrocortisone cream. These products will also relieve the itch. If creams and lotions aren’t enough to soothe itchy skin, ask your doctor whether you should take an antihistamine or steroid medicine by mouth.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Don’t scratch! Though the rash might itch, resist the urge to scratch or pick at the blisters. You could get an infection.\nWhen should I get medical help for poison ivy, oak, or sumac?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Go to the emergency room if you have:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Trouble breathing or swallowing\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Rashes or blisters on a large part of your body, or on your face or genitals\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Swelling, especially of the eyes\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- An itch you can’t relieve, no matter what medicine or lotion you use\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A fever over 100 F\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A rash that hasn’t gone away after a few weeks
    </string>
    <string name="sprain">
What’s the difference between a sprain and strain?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Sprains and strains are common injuries. Here’s how to tell the difference:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A sprain is a stretch or tear of a ligament, the tough tissue that connects bones and supports the joints. You’re most likely to get a sprain in the wrist or ankle. Sprains cause pain, bruising, and swelling. You may have trouble moving the joint.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- A strain is an injury to a muscle or tendon, the thick tissue that attaches muscles to bones. You’re most likely to get a strain in your back or hamstring muscles. Strains cause pain, weakness, swelling, and muscle cramps. You may have trouble moving the muscle.\nHow do I treat sprains and strains?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009For a mild sprain or strain:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Rest the limb to give it a chance to heal.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Hold ice on the area for 20 minutes at a time, four to eight times a day, to bring down swelling. Don’t use heat — it could make the area swell even more.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wrap an elastic bandage or splint around the sprain or strain.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Put a pillow under the injured body part to keep it raised.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Take over-the-counter medicines such as ibuprofen to relieve the pain.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009For a more severe sprain or strain, where there’s a lot of pain, swelling, and you have trouble moving around, see your doctor. You may need crutches or physical therapy.
    </string>
    <string name="stroke">
The FAST guide is the most important thing to remember when dealing with people who have had a stroke. The earlier they receive treatment, the better. Phone for emergency medical help straight away.\nIf you think a person has had a stroke, use the FAST guide:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Facial weakness – is the person unable to smile evenly, or are their eyes or mouth droopy?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Arm weakness – is the person only able to raise one arm?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Speech problems – is the person unable to speak clearly or understand you?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Time to phone 999 or 112 – for emergency help if a person has any of these symptoms.
    </string>
    <string name="thorns">
How do I remove a splinter?\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009Splinters are more of an annoyance than a real health problem, but if you’ve got one stuck in a finger or toe, you’ll want to get it out. How you remove a splinter depends on how deep it is.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If the splinter is sticking out of the skin:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wash the skin around the splinter with soap and water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Clean a pair of tweezers with a cotton swab dipped in alcohol.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Grab the end of the splinter with the tweezers.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Pull it out at the same angle as the splinter went in.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Clean the skin again with soap and water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009If the splinter is under the skin:\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Wash the skin around the splinter with soap and water.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Clean a needle and tweezers with alcohol.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Gently scrape away the skin above the splinter with the needle until you can see the top of the splinter.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Grab the end of the splinter with the tweezers and pull it out at the same angle it went in.\n\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009- Clean the skin again with soap and water.
    </string>
    //BMI
    <string name="bmi_age">Age</string>
    <string name="bmi_height">Height</string>
    <string name="bmi_weight">Weight</string>
    <string name="bmi_category">Category</string>
    <string name="bmi_difference">Difference</string>
    <string name="bmi_height_unit">Choose Height Unit</string>
    <string name="bmi_weight_unit">Choose Weight Unit</string>
    <string name="bmi_severe_thin">Severe Thinness</string>
    <string name="bmi_moderate_thin">Moderate Thinness</string>
    <string name="bmi_mild_thin">Mild Thinness</string>
    <string name="bmi_normal">Normal</string>
    <string name="bmi_overweight">Overweight</string>
    <string name="bmi_obese_1">Obese Class I"</string>
    <string name="bmi_obese_2">Obese Class II"</string>
    <string name="bmi_obese_3">Obese Class III"</string>

    //Notifications
    <string name="noti_friendreq">has sent you a friend request</string>
    <string name="noti_friendac">has accepted your friend request</string>
    <string name="noti_acfriend">You have accepted friend request of</string>
    <string name="noti_clock">remind you to take medicine</string>

    //
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="create">Create</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment" translatable="false">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="facebook_app_id" translatable="false">231858022860423</string>
    <string name="fb_login_protocol_scheme" translatable="false">fb231858022860423</string>
    <string name="facebook_client_token" translatable="false">d1677367d8ec13b0d62306e2a214ed17</string>
    <string name="my_web_client_id" translatable="false">1087708714921-2aqkkui04lu1r214ocogmgbtf7vr4hub.apps.googleusercontent.com</string>
    <string name="title_activity_first_aid">First Aid</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bmi">BMI Calculator</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hospital_map">Hospital Map</string>
    <string name="button_hospital_map">Hospital Map</string>
    <string name="button_hospital_list">Hospital List</string>
    <string name="normal_map">Normal Map</string>
    <string name="hybrid_map">Hybrid Map</string>
    <string name="satellite_map">Satellite Map</string>
    <string name="terrain_map">Terrain Map</string>
    <string name="lat_long_snippet" translatable="false">Lat: %1$.5f, Long: %2$.5f</string>
    <string name="dropped_pin">Dropped Pin</string>
    <string name="poi" translatable="false">poi</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>

    <string name="app_name_main">Healthcare app</string>
    <string name="change_email">Change Email</string>
    <string name="change_info">Change Profile</string>
    <string name="change_email_description">To change email you need to enter your current password</string>
    <string name="current_password">Current password</string>
    <string name="authenticate">Authenticate</string>
    <string name="new_email">New email</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="birthday">Birthday</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="email_login">Email Login</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="password_hint">Enter your password</string>
    <string name="confirm_password">Confirm Password</string>
    <string name="confirm_password_hint">Confirm your password</string>
    <string name="forget_password_ask">Forgot password?</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="logout">Logout</string>
    <string name="login_google">Login with google</string>
    <string name="login_facebook">Login with facebook</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="message">Message</string>
    <string name="profile">Profile</string>
    <string name="edit_profile">Edit profile</string>
    <string name="notification">Notification</string>
    <string name="email_updated">Email updated</string>
    <string name="email_updated_description">Your email has been updated!</string>
    <string name="password_updated_description">Your password has been updated!</string>
    <string name="password_updated">Password updated</string>
    <string name="forget_password">Forget password</string>
    <string name="forget_password_description">Provide your account\'s email for which you want to reset your password!</string>
    <string name="ask_not_account">Don\'t have an account yet?</string>
    <string name="ask_have_account">Already have an account?</string>
    <string name="ask_sign_up">Sign up now!</string>
    <string name="sign_up">Sign up</string>
    <string name="email_address">Email address</string>
    <string name="email_address_hint">Enter your email</string>
    <string name="full_name">Full name</string>
    <string name="full_name_hint">Enter your full name</string>
    <string name="change_password">Change password</string>
    <string name="information">Information</string>
    <string name="friend_request">Friend request</string>
    <string name="cancel_friend_request">Cancel friend request</string>
    <string name="accept_friend_request">Accept friend request</string>
    <string name="send_friend_request">Send friend request</string>
    <string name="unfriend">Unfriend</string>
    <string name="drug_interaction">Drug interaction</string>
    <string name="health_advice">Health advice</string>
    <string name="skin_disease">Skin disease</string>
    //About us
    <string name="description">Description about our app</string>
    <string name="description_script">Our application helps users improve their health through their work. Support searching and consulting for diseases, drugs, medical examination places, etc. anytime, anywhere; At the same time, you can set a schedule to take medicine for yourself and monitor the disease status of a family member.</string>
    <string name="version">Version 1.0</string>
    <string name="connect_us">Connect with us!</string>
    <string name="copyright">Copyright 2023 by CKDP</string>
    <string name="phone_no">Phone number</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy</string>
    <string name="aboutus">About us</string>
    <string name="_0903612640" translatable="false">0903612640</string>
    <string name="email_contact" translatable="false">ktphanmem20@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="reference" >Our reference</string>
    <string name="google_reference_item1" >API for map:</string>
    <string name="google_reference_item2" >API for list of nearby hospitals:</string>
    <string name="google_reference_item3" >API for calculating distance:</string>
    <string name="ai_reference_item1" >API for Assistant ChatGPT:</string>
    <string name="ai_reference_item2" >API FOR detect-skin-disease:</string>
    <string name="ai_reference_item3" >API for drug:</string>

    <!--app  name-->
    <string name="dark_mode">Dark Mode</string>
    <string name="dark_mode_def_value" translatable="false">1</string>

    <string name="language">Language</string>
    <string name="language_def_value" translatable="false">1</string>

    <string-array name="language_entries">
        <item>English</item>
        <item>Vietnamese</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="language_values">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>

    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_anaphylaxis">Anaphulaxis</string>
    <string name="advanced">Advanced</string>
    <string name="alarm_tiltle">Alarm</string>
    <string name="hospital_map">Hospital map</string>
    <string name="alarm">Alarm</string>
    <string name="alarm_setting">Alarm Settings</string>

    <!--=======-->
    <!--    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>-->
    <!--    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>-->
    <!--    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>-->
    <!--&gt;>>>>>> Stashed changes-->
</resources>